[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：所以最后两个练习是对
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So those last two exercises are the introduction to
安全的主题。
the subject of security.
安全是一个非常重要的话题，而且
And security is a really, really important topic, and
不幸的是，在我们行业的任何层面上都没有得到很好的理解。
unfortunately it's not well understood at any level in our industry.
因此，有些人认为安全是戴着看不见的彩色帽子的人之间的战争。
So, some people think of security as a war between people in invisible colored hats.
他们是白帽子的家伙和黑帽子的家伙，而且
They're the white hat guys and the black hat guys, and
白帽子的人可能是好人，黑帽子的人可能是坏人，
the white hat guys are probably good guys and black hat guys are probably bad guys,
除了有著名的白帽，以前是黑帽，还有黑帽
except there are famous white hats that used to be black hats, and black hats
曾经是白帽和灰帽的人似乎是两面派。
who used to be white hats and grey hats who seem to be playing both sides.
事实证明，你不能很容易地通过看不见的帽子来识别一个人。
And it turns out you cannot easily identify somebody by their invisible hat.
这是一种不起作用的安全模式。
That this is a model of security that just doesn't work.
安全不是帽子的问题。
Security is not about hats.
更糟糕的是这个模型
The thing that's even worse about that model is that it
说安全属于专家，这种模式不起作用。
says that security belongs to the specialists, and that model doesn't work.
所以在专家模型中，这意味着您有负责的安全专家
So in the specialist model it means you've got security experts who are responsible
所有的安全，没有其他人对安全负责。
for all the security and nobody else is responsible for security.
事实上，其他所有人都在与那些帮助我们的人作对
And in fact everybody else is working against the guys who are helping to
处理安全问题，这种模式根本就不有效。
deal with security and that model is not effective at all.
不安全感的一个后果或一个来源就是事情发生了变化。
One consequence of, or one source of insecurity is that things change.
可能是在有限的范围内或有限的上下文中，您可以做一些事情
It might be that within a limited scope or a limited context you could do things and
这样做没有安全漏洞。
there's no security vulnerability in doing that.
但是后来，事情发生了变化，范围扩大了，或者其他什么。
But then, things change, the scope increases, or whatever.
而现在这突然变成了一个很大的安全问题。
And now suddenly that turns into a big security problem.
对于目的或用途来说，这并不是不寻常的，或者
It is not unusual for the purpose or use or
要在其生命周期内更改的软件范围。
scope of software to change over its life.
很少在上下文中重新检查软件系统的安全属性
Rarely are the security properties of software systems reexamined in the context
新的或不断发展的任务。
of new or evolving missions.
这会导致系统不安全。
This leads to insecure systems.
你知道这是谁写的吗？
You know who wrote this?
是我写的那就是我。
I did, I wrote that, that's me.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：所以我将给你们一套原则。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So I'm going to be giving you a set of principles.
其中大部分都很简单，很明显，一旦你有了它，
And most of them are pretty simple and pretty obvious and once you've got it,
你可以自己对安全问题进行推理。
you're able to reason about security on your own.
安全世界是令人难以置信的复杂，而且
The world of security is incredibly complicated, and
总是在变化，任何人都不可能掌握它，
is always changing, and it's impossible for any human to keep on top of it,
尤其是一个有白天工作的人，根本没有办法。
particularly a human who has a day job, there's just no way.
但这套原则实际上很小，如果你能理解
But the set of principles is actually very small and if you can understand
原则，你可以自己解决剩下的大部分问题。
the principles, you can work out most of the rest of it on your own.
安全性不是通过诡计或黑客获得的，
Security is not obtained by tricks or hacks,
如果你遇到有人说，我们可以通过做这个把戏来保护我们的系统，
if you ever encounter someone who says, we can secure our system by doing this trick,
那个人不是被误导就是在撒谎。
that person is either misinformed or lying.
因为事实证明花招是行不通的，
Because it turns out tricks don't work,
只有坚持原则才能奏效。
it's only adherence to principles that works.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：所以首要原则之一是
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So one of the first principles for
计算机系统的在线安全是威慑不是有效的，
online security of computer systems is that deterrence is not effective,
那是因为你不能惩罚一个看不见的攻击者。
and that's because you can't punish an invisible attacker.
现在现实世界中，威慑是非常有效的。
Now in the real world, deterrence is very effective.
这就是为什么我们还没有把自己炸飞。
That's why we have not blown ourselves up yet.
但是在网上，攻击者在攻击你的时候不需要醒着
But online an attacker doesn't need to be awake while he's attacking you so
你不能对看不见或看不见的人构成威胁
there's no threat you can make to someone you can't see or
触摸以阻止他们做事情。
touch to prevent them from doing things.
所以唯一有效的就是预防，
So the only thing that works is prevention,
预防是唯一有效的机制。
prevention is the only effective mechanism.
所以我要在这里停下来给你们讲一个关于约翰·马丁·施莱尔的故事。
So I'm gonna stop here and tell you a story about Johann Martin Schleyer.
施莱尔是巴伐利亚的一名牧师
Schleyer was a priest living in Bavaria and
一天晚上，上帝在梦中来到他身边，告诉他做点什么。
one night God came to him in a dream and told him to do something.
现在，为了理解这个故事，我需要告诉你们一个更早的故事。
Now in order to understand that story I need to tell you an earlier story.
很久以前，在希纳平原上，世界上最好的建筑师，
Long, long ago on the plain of Shinar, the world's best architects,
建造者、工程师、材料专家和
builders, engineers, material specialists, and
工人们聚集在一起建造了一座通向天堂的塔。
workers got together to build a tower that would reach to heaven.
这是当时世界历史上最大的建筑项目。
It was the biggest construction project in the history of the world at that point.
这是一个令人惊异的项目，上帝对此并不高兴。
It was amazing project and God was not happy about it.
我们不知道他对这个项目的抱怨是什么
We don't know what his complaint about the project was but
他不想让它成功，所以他决定让这个项目失败。
he did not want it succeeding, so he decided to cause the project to fail.
对于如何让项目失败，他有很多选择。
And he had a lot of options available as to how he was going to fail the project.
他可能会引起地震，他可能会淹没飞机，
He could have caused earthquakes, he could have flooded the plane,
他本可以把雷电扔在他们身上。
he could have thrown thunderbolts down on them.
相反，他决定下去混淆他们的讲话。
Instead he decided to go down and confuse their speech.
在他这样做之后，他们说话的时候就不能再互相理解了，
And after he did that they could no longer understand each other when they spoke,
无法沟通项目崩溃，以及
and being unable to communicate the project collapsed, and
他们都迷失了方向，建立了自己的国家。
they all wandered off and started their own countries.
基本上是他制造了i18n问题。
Basically he created the i18n problem.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：所以几千年后他来到施莱耶
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So thousands of years later he comes to Schleyer while
他睡着了，说，我改变主意了，我想要什么
he's sleeping and says, I've changed my mind about that, and what I want
你现在要做的就是创造一种世界上每个人都能理解的语言。
you to do now is to create a language that everybody in the world can understand.
所以Schleyer醒了，他开始学习他的语言，他称之为Volapuk。
So Schleyer wakes up and he begins working on his language, which he calls Volapuk.
Volapuk是Volapuk中的单词，意思是世界说话。
Volapuk being the word in Volapuk, meaning world speak.
他的词汇量是以英语为基础的，但是
He based his vocabulary on English, but
他把它改造得如此之大，以至于对说英语的人来说一点帮助都没有。
he transformed it so much that it is no help to English speakers at all.
很难看到里面的文字世界和演讲，
It's hard to see the words world and speech in there,
但这就是根的来源。
but that's where the roots came from.
他被告知说英语的人对变音没有问题。
And he was told that English speakers did not have a problem with umlauts.
但我可以告诉你，这个说英语的人在变音方面有很多麻烦。
But I can tell you this English speaker has a lot of trouble with umlauts.
但他还是出版了他的语言。
But he published his language anyway.
他工作了大约一年，然后
He worked for about a year and then and
1880年用德语出版了一本关于Volapuk的书。
published a book in German about Volapuk in 1880.
现在人们在Schleyer之前已经设计人工语言很多年了。
Now people had been designing artificial languages for many years before Schleyer.
英国的约翰·威尔金斯和保罗·加诺也在做类似的事情
There was John Wilkins and Paul Garneau in England were doing similar
各种各样的东西，而且在之后出现了很多人工语言
sorts of things, and there been lots of artificial languages after but
施莱尔在正确的时间做了这件事。
Schleyer was doing this at just the right time.
几个世纪以来，欧洲一直处于相当稳定的战争状态，
Europe had been in a fairly constant state of war for centuries and
人们真的对此感到厌倦了。
people were getting really tired of it.
他们观察了刚刚在美国发生的内战，
And they observed what had just happened in the U.S with their civil war,
新技术第一次出现在战场上
where new technologies were coming onto the battlefield for the first time and
那里发生的可怕的破坏。
the terrible devastation that happened there.
他们非常担心这会变得非常糟糕
And they were very concerned that this was going to get really, really bad and
人们对解决世界和平问题非常感兴趣。
there was a lot of interest in trying to solve the world peace problem.
他们中的很多人都认为Volapuk是实现这一目标的一种方法。
And a lot of them saw Volapuk as a method for doing that.
Volapuk将允许我们经历去盲目化，
That Volapuk would allow us to experience de-babelization,
我们将打破国与国之间的语言障碍，也许如果
where we would break down the language barriers between countries and maybe if
我们可以更有效地沟通，也许即将到来的战争可以避免。
we can communicate more effectively, maybe the coming war could be avoided.
因此，Volapuk运动在世界各地开始兴起，不仅仅是欧洲，而是
And so the Volapuk movement took off all over the world, not just Europe but
到处都是。
everywhere.
在世界各地的城市中，正在创建沃尔拉普克社会。
In cities all over the world Volapuk societies were being created.
关于和在Volapuk出版的书籍。
Books were being published about and in Volapuk.
新的期刊正在用Volapuk写，每个月都会上线，
New journals were being written in Volapuk, coming online every month,
它影响到了社会的各个阶层。
and it was reaching all classes of society.
学习这些东西的不仅仅是智力精英。
It wasn't just the intellectual elites learning this stuff.
每个人都对Volapuk感兴趣，它真的开始起飞了。
Everybody was interested in Volapuk and it was really taking off.
这门语言的成功在很大程度上要归功于这个家伙。
And a lot of the success of the language was due to this guy.
这是Auguste Kerckhoff
This is Auguste Kerckhoffs.
他是一位荷兰语言学家，他写了大量关于Volapuk和
He was a Dutch linguist, and he wrote extensively about Volapuk and
在世界各地传授语言。
traveled all over the world teaching the language.
他成功地做到了这一点，但在第二次沃拉普克会议上，
And he was so successful at doing that but at the Second Volapuk Conference,
他被选为Volapuk研究所所长，并且
he was elected to be director of the Volapuk Institute, and
考虑到在全世界推广Volapuk的工作。
given the job of popularizing Volapuk throughout the world.
第二年在第三次大会上，
The next year at the Third Congress,
在那次大会上，他们做了沃尔帕克国会的所有事务，
at that Congress they did all of the business in the Congress in Volapuk,
就连招待饭菜的服务员也在说沃拉普克，
even the waiters serving the meals were speaking Volapuk,
Kerckhoff在那次会议上提出了对语言的修改。
and Kerckhoffs at that meeting proposed a change to the language.
语言中有一些很少使用的情绪，非常
There were some moods in the language which were rarely used, that were very
复杂和困难的教和学，Kerckhoff提出
complicated and difficult to teach and learn and Kerckhoffs was proposing that
它们被从语言中删除，以便让每个人都能更容易地使用它。
they be removed from the language in order to make it more accessible to everybody.
基本上是Volapuk，好的部分。
Basically Volapuk, the good parts.
我爱这家伙。
I love this guy.
他很棒。
He was great.
施莱尔对此非常沮丧。
Schleyer was extremely upset about this.
施莱耶坚持认为这门语言属于他
Schleyer insisted that the language belonged to him and
他要求否决国会可能提出的任何建议。
he demanded a veto over anything that the Congress might propose.
在这一点上，运动分叉。
At that point the movement forked.
大约有一半的与会者是德国代表团的成员，他们跟着
About half of the attendees were in the German delegation and they went with
Schleyer，其他人都和Kerckhoff一起去了，然后突然一片混乱。
Schleyer, everybody else went with Kerckhoffs, and then suddenly chaos.
他们都是狡猾的语言学家，他们说只要我们提出
They're all these cunning linguists who said well as long as we're proposing
改变我得到了一些想法，他们开始抛出新的功能
changes I got some ideas, and they started throwing new features out for
能进入沃拉普克的东西。
what could go into Volapuk.
其他人说，世界语是一门更好的语言，
And other people saying well, Esperanto's a better language,
我们应该选那个。
we should go with that one.
然后那东西倒塌了。
And the thing collapsed.
几乎一夜之间Volapuk就死了。
Almost overnight Volapuk was dead.
所以我们不知道如果Volapuk成功了会发生什么
So we don't know what would have happened had Volapuk succeeded,
但我们知道Volapuk失败后发生了什么
but we do know what happened after Volapuk failed,
世界经历了历史上最血腥的一个世纪。
that the world had its bloodiest century in history.
所以他们最终被重新宝贝化了。
So they ended up with re-babelization.
崩溃后，他们的语言比开始时更多。
After it collapsed they had more languages than when they started.
人们继续设计语言，这类似于
And people continue to design languages, it's similar to the compulsion that causes
有些人设计编程语言。
some people to design programming languages.
圣人的设计者，你还记得那个电视节目和电影吗？
The guy who designed the Saint, you remember that TV show and the movie?
他设计了一种叫做旧石器的语言。
He designed a language called Paleo Neo.
设计棋盘游戏，事业，
The guy who designed the board game, Careers,
设计了一种叫做中间语言的语言。
designed a language called Interlingua.
也许所有语言设计师中最著名的是JRR Tolkien，
Maybe the most famous of all language designers was JRR Tolkien,
谁为史诗般的种族设计语言，像精灵和
who designed languages for epic races like elves and
侏儒，并用这些语言写了史诗
dwarves, and wrote epic poetry in those languages and
然后写历史来解释那些史诗的背景。
then wrote histories to explain the context of those epics.
然后用所有这些作为“指环王”的背景故事。
And then used all of that as the back story to the Lord Of The Rings.
他曾经做过一次关于他的强迫症的报告。
He once gave a talk about his compulsion.
他称之为秘密恶习。
He called it a secret vice.
有没有人碰巧知道世界上最流行的发明语言是什么？
Anybody happen to know what the most popular invented language in the world
是今天吗？
is today?
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：克林贡语。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Klingon.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：很好，这是克林贡。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Very good, it is Klingon.